what we create runs everywhere
我们创造的东西遍布全球
it's literally used everywhere in the world
或者换句话说，全球各地都在使用
today without the Apache，the internet
如果没有 Apache，
that we know today would not have happened。
就没有人人在用的互联网
the best database，the best streaming framework.
没有更好的数据库和流框架。
We're creating industry's.
我们创建了一个新的产业。
Programming for fun.
为乐趣而编程。
People
It's a great group of people.
这是一群很优秀的人。
It's connecting people. It's building bridges
它把大家紧密联系在一起。它架起一座桥，
people from China people from Europe.
贯通中国和欧洲。
It doesn't matter what language you speak
不管讲什么语言
where you come from
来自何地
Apache is really good at bringing people together
Apache 都能把人们召集在一起
and letting them work together
工作
without companies getting in the way.
不受公司限制。
Try to learn something from everybody every day.
我们向他人学习
Inspiring， it makes me want to be better.
成为更好的自己。
When working with people,
和这些
there are so much better than yourself
优秀的人在一起，
you learn a lot. Community，community in more community.
你会受益匪浅。 一个个小社区组成更大的社区。
People were so open and
大家都很开放
so engaging and so excited to help.
很投入，乐于助人。
Don't be afraid to give, to share, you would get more out of it.
不要害怕给予、分享， 你会收获很多。
I've got more out of Apache
Apache 给予我的，远远超过
than I've ever given.
我的付出。
Building communities around people who are
这群人激情澎湃，
passionate about solving problems.
喜欢解决各种问题，
Create incredibly passionate communities who
构建一个激情四射的共同体，
are then empowered to create incredibly powerful software.
然后依托这样的共同体，创建功能强大的软件
The software that we've written
我们编写的软件
how far it's gone and how
能走多远
much it's used every day is staggering
能被多少人使用
I'm proud to be a part of an
这个组织在改变世界，
organization that has changed the world
能成为其中一员，我倍感自豪
and I don't think many people understand
可能很多人还不了解
exactly how Apache has changed the world.
Apache 如何改变了整个世界。
It's impacted everyone when there's
它影响甚远
something now you know people can touch
包括你每天接触到的物品
and interact with their phones and
和手机、汽车的交互
their car. And you know you realize all
当你会意识到
of them are open-source software and it's like
这些都是开源的时， 你会感叹
wow okay this is something that's truly
开源软件真的在
changed the world.
改变世界。
You know it's more than just technology
这不仅仅是技术，
it's more than just coding. It's bringing
不仅仅是代码
new ideas new aspects there's so much
它更是一种新思想，
more we can do with the technology.
科技创造价值，
We already have that is something that's
我们已经拥有了
that's amazing
令人惊叹的
with the foundation. That is something
基金会,
it's so exciting, and that is the thing
令人振奋的成就,
that really sort of keeps me interested
它（基金会)一直吸引着我、
in and I'm passionate about.
让我充满激情。
There's still so much work to do, so like
未来的路还很长（路漫漫其修远兮），
I'm gonna be busy for a while I think
我会全力以赴为之奋斗（吾将上下而求索），
doing this kind of work and and I hope
我希望大家
many other people are too.
都会为之奋斗不息
The best software in the world I mean
世界上最好的软件，
that's the ASF
就是 ASF